Transcription by CastingWords
She's been in the hospital forever.
I feel bad for him. He's been alone all this time.
Father won't forgive you, you know.
Excuse me?
What makes you think that I've forgiven him? I still remember. He branded his own daughter a failure when she was a middle school student.
He said there are other things in life than Shogi. As if he really believed that.
But what he said is true. There are other things in life than Shogi.
Don't you lie to me too! Shogi is the only thing you and Dad ever think about. I've had enough of this. The way that you look at me. You make me feel like I'm a loser. You both always tiptoe around me.
It's infuriating. I hate it. Both of you judging me. How long do I have to feel this pathetic?
Then I'll leave instead. If I go, I'm sure that no one will really worry about me.
But it's different with you. You are important to Father. Even if you don't realize it.
In all things, the path should have a teacher or not.
10 a.m. The game's starting. The tournament final to determine who the challenger will be for the Shishio title. It's the first of three matches.
Right now, gathered in the special match room, the two players are facing each other.
I wonder what kind of battle it'll be.
When I was playing against Mr. Shimada, a strange feeling came over me.
It was like I'd stepped into a sea of trees and became entangled by something powerful.
It was like something silently tightening around me.
What kind of game will he play when he goes up against Goto?
Um, excuse me. Here are my absence notices for March.
Oh, Kiriyama. Look at this. It's amazing.
Huh?
Two hours in and this is where they're at.
So, there.
One look and I could tell by the moves they had played already that this was going to be an all-out slugfest.
I was wondering how those two would stack up against each other. It looks like they're going blow for blow.
They're crazy.
Hmm.
You should go.
Go where, sir?
To Shogi Hall.
Uh, but...
This isn't a title match, so they won't be updating the blog in real time.
Wouldn't it be more educational if you were there watching it in person?
But I have so many absences.
Ow!
It's fine! Just go!
He does have enough days, right?
One, two, three...
Yeah.
He'll barely make it, I think.
What am I doing?
I'm an awful teacher!
Huh?
Hey, Kiriyama.
Kiriyama?
Oh, look!
Gold to 4-3!
No way.
I've never seen Mr. Shimada like this.
Oh?
Is he sacrificing his bishop?
I've never seen him play like this before, either.
It felt like their presence came from the special match room,
then made its way through the dark hallway,
and now could be felt in this room.
Oh, my God!
Why?
How?
What's so different?
Why are each of their moves so fascinating?
Is it the amount of time they've been playing?
The depth of experience they had acquired?
The weight of all of their sacrifices?
Or is it all of the above?
That's right.
These two.
They have complete faith in their own abilities.
A battle of will.
The match ended at 9pm,
when Shimada Eighth Den conceded defeat.
That was it.
The first game of the Shishio Championship Finals Tournament,
and Goto Ninth Den is the winner.
Hey, Rei.
This place hasn't changed a bit.
It's such a dreary building.
I used to hate it here,
on this dark street,
as well as that gloomy shrine.
Kyoko.
Well, if it isn't my two stalkers here together.
What now, Kyoko?
Well, after all, I...
And you?
You were just raring to take me on, huh?
Shimada knocked you out.
What happened?
Never underestimate A-class.
Wait, are you really leaving?
I didn't want to leave.
Hey, wait a minute!
Are you running?
Away from me?
But,
I couldn't be with her anymore.
I was in a hurry to grow up.
I thought if I couldn't stand on my own two feet,
then there was no way I could protect them.
Those who meant the most to me.
I didn't win.
I tried to push with the one-turn-loss bishop exchange,
but that bastard fought back immediately.
He was cheerful.
That old man really is tough.
Him and that scary face.
For someone so strong,
he's surprisingly childish.
Still,
I swear I won't lose next time.
Yeah!
I know you can do it!
I see.
That's tough.
I can see why he's stayed away.
Mm-hmm.
He made promises to you girls,
but then he failed to deliver.
It's hard for a young boy.
At his age,
it can be almost mortifying.
Ah!
If it were me,
I'd slit my belly.
Well,
if it were me,
I'd seclude myself up in the mountains.
Ah!
Really?
It's that embarrassing?
But it wouldn't change the way we see him.
He said he'd try his hardest,
so I'm sure he did all he could.
That's how he is.
Even if it didn't work out,
no one would laugh at him.
Exactly.
Shame can strengthen you.
Huh?
Because if you should fail,
it means you've challenged yourself.
That's a hell of a lot better
than a life of doing nothing
but laughing at other people.
The thing is,
the kid is still young
and too damn serious.
He must have really wanted to beat that other guy.
I've never seen Ray show so much fighting spirit before.
He was so fired up.
Yeah.
Well,
I guess he bit off more than he could chew.
I bet all he's eating now
is just sweet buns and ramen, huh?
What do you think we should do?
I feel sad.
You just gotta leave him be for now.
The only way to make up for a blunder at work
is to work harder to fix it.
Until he comes to terms with what happened,
he'll be stuck.
In the meantime,
he'll have to try his best.
He'll figure this stuff out when he's older.
It's no big secret.
Of all the people in the world
who've put themselves out there,
every one of them
has been humiliated themselves
at some point.
Hey, Shimada.
Seems to me
that you look even older than I do.
I don't know what you're talking about.
It must be pretty difficult
for a man your age
to try and stay in shape.
Don't tell me
you've been secretly working out.
Must be tough
for a narcissist.
You think so, chum?
Shall we go now?
That was so cool.
They give off such a confident aura.
I wonder what they were saying.
Shimada is so cool.
So that's it.
That's the kind of thing
that happens when you make it to A class.
That's strange.
I can't smell the slightest bit of aura on me.
Since I'm B1,
do I have to move up to A class
to smell like that?
I bet that's it.
That's when you'll have that aura, too.
Come on, let's go.
It's time.
Their match is gonna start.
Right.
I don't think you guys
will ever have it.
At least not while you're
spying behind bushes.
Hmm.
As you can see,
Germany's strong recovery
of productivity
at the end of World War I
It's almost 10 o'clock.
The match is about to start.
Three matches determine
who goes to the championship.
Goto Ninth Den
won the first match.
This is Mr. Shimada's last chance.
During the previous match,
they unexpectedly slugged it out.
What kind of battle
will it be this time?
Damn it.
I want to watch so badly.
But I can't.
Okay.
I just finished calculating
your attendance records.
And I've come to the conclusion
that you're not allowed
to catch a cold
or have an illness of any kind.
You've already got
two scheduled days off
for ranking competition,
so we can't do anything about that.
But if you happen to advance
in any of the tournaments,
you'll be at the edge of a cliff.
Also, in case something should happen,
aim to get higher than average scores
on all of the year-end tests, okay?
As for what's going to be covered
on those tests,
I'd say you could ask a friend,
but by the time you found one,
the exam would be over.
Instead, I asked all of the teachers
for the materials on your behalf.
Here, don't lose this.
Okay, then.
You've got to pass.
If you don't,
your classmates will start
calling you old man.
You're right, Mr. Hayashida.
Thanks a lot.
This is a big help.
But now,
why do I feel like crap?
You're right.
No!
It's a slugfest. Again. Look at them. They're just so intense.
In fact, they're using more brute force now than last time.
No way. They're insane. They're using their kings to fight.
Why? What are you guys doing? It's so immature.
Who would think that playing the king would be a good way to win?
It's completely reckless.
That was real thunder. Now their pieces are glowing with electricity.
Huh?
Guess who won, kiddo?
Yes! I knew you'd win! That was awesome!
After one match, he's exhausted!
What's the matter, kiddo?
Oh, it's just that...
Kyriyama hasn't texted me back yet.
I see.
Maybe I went a little too far on the last match.
Hmm...
Tell me, why are you so interested in Kyriyama getting better?
Well, I guess...
It's because he...
He had the courage to knock me down.
Then, he pulled me back up again.
I spent a lot of time in the hospital when I was just a little kid.
The only thing that got me through it was studying everything I could about Shogi.
While all the other kids my age were outside having fun and playing, there I was, completely immersed in Shogi.
And yet, the stronger I got, the more I would write off my weaker opponents.
I thought they were just cowards that didn't try.
It was so annoying and frustrating.
I was sick of it.
Then, when I was nothing but a lump of ego...
Um...
Here...
Have some.
That's when...
I met Kyriyama.
He knocked me to the ground.
And saved me.
There is someone stronger than me.
Someone who's put in more effort than me.
He made me realize that I'm not alone.
I see.
Hmm.
I can understand that.
Kinda.
Wait a second!
Hey!
Hey, come on!
Wait a minute!
Wait!
Wait a' second!
Ha ha ha!
What the hell!
What the hell?
Goto, you moron!
That's it! I've had it with you!
Wait, but Goto is a married man.
Then who's that?
She's so beautiful and young.
Did they just have an argument?
What is this sense of defeat?
No!
That was nothing at all!
I'll win the next run too, dammit!
Come on, kiddo. Let's get back.
We have to plan for the final match!
Yes! There it is!
That's what I'm talking about!
I'm sorry. You were actually already two days short.
I see. It's okay. It's all my fault anyway.
I'm the one who's sorry.
All right, then. What shall we do for the girls' festival at our house this year?
Well, shall we get started?
Oh, no. I completely forgot why I was here.
If he doesn't want to come over to our house anymore, then fine.
Hinawe Sushi, hurry up! Mama wants her right now! Right now!
March comes in like a lion. Hey, you better watch it, too.
I know. I get it already. You better not miss it, either.
Thank you.